# Peganov Nikita

## **Backend Developer**

Backend developer with working experience in highload systems and project organization. Specialize in Java, Python and C++ with 3 years of production development experience. I like to create IT-startups, generate ideas and learn new technologies. I prefer to work in Moscow or online.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Yandex, Moscow

July 2022 - October 2022

Intern Python/Java Developer of a compensation calculation system in HR-Tech

- added processing of uploads to the system reducing user work time by 50%
- implemented uploading of all user data to the cloud to increase system fault tolerance
- solved 23 minor tasks and wrote unit tests for them to improve the system

Yandex, Moscow

July 2021 — November 2021

Intern Python Developer in traffic management team

- $\bullet$  reduced by 50% the load on the servers with DB by translating readonly requests to replicas
- added ipv6 processing into balancers' work allowed to use new ip's without extra 900 lines
- $\bullet$  created an internal library redirecting the request to the nearest datacenter

Freelance July 2020 — July 2021

- $\bullet$  wrote scripts parsing sites for market analytics
- launched vk bots for online games with a maximum load of 63 people
- developed a telegram bot for the 365 good deeds project

## **PROJECTS**

Huawei, Moscow

November 2021 - May 2022

Python Developer, Data Scientist

Research work «Reinforcement learning for resource allocation tasks in the cloud»

- tested the applicability of reinforcement learning in real conditions
- created and trained a neural network processing 4500 requests per hour
- the total number of processed requests was 1.5 million

## Startup SmartLearning, Moscow

November 2020 - March 2021

Kotlin Developer, SEO the development of the Android-application for quick learning

- assembled and managed a team of 4 programmers
- developed an Android application downloaded by 183 users
- took the 19th place at the HSE Fest startup competition

## Wikirace. Summer Informatics School

June 2018 — July 2018

Python Developer in an online-game where you need to find a way between wikipedia pages

- wrote a script that processed 1.8 million wikipedia articles
- implemented the back button which increased user convenience
- $\bullet$  added multiplayer increasing the number of players by 30%

## EDUCATION

# Higher School of Economics, Moscow

Since September 2020

Bachelor in Computer Science

- $\bullet$  Graduated courses with excellence: C++ Programming, Introduction to Applied Analytics, Databases, Calculus, Discrete Mathematics, English for Business Purposes
- $\bullet \ Completed \ courses: \ Operating \ Systems, Software \ Design \ on \ Java, \ Algorithms \ and \ Data \ Structures, \ Computer \ System \ Architecture, \ Algebra, Software \ Development \ Methodologies, \ Probability \ Theory \ Normality \ Computer \ System \ Algebra, Software \ Development \ Methodologies, \ Probability \ Theory \ Normality \ Computer \ System \ Normality \ Computer \ Normality \ Normality \ Computer \ Normality \ Computer \ Normality \ Computer \ Normality \ Normality \ Computer \ Normality \ Nor$
- •Research works in the field of neural networks were rated 9 out of 10 by scientific supervisors

#### Moscow, Russia

t.me/peganov\_ns
peganov.nik@gmail.com
+7 (977) 744-19-23
vk.com/nikpeg
github.com/NikPeg
gitlab.com/peganov.nik

# COMPUTER SKILLS Python (Django, Jupyter,

numpy, sympy, sklearn)

Java (Sockets, JavaFX,
Multithreading, Derby)
C/C++
(Multithreading, STL)
C#
(Requests, Windows forms)
Kotlin (Android)
SQL

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

(SQLite, PostgreSQL)

Git
Linux
Docker
Selenium
JetBrains IDEs

## **LANGUAGES**

English (B2)
Russian (Native speaker)

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winner of ITMO "Open Olympiad of schoolchildren in computer science" (2020) Winner of "United Mathematical Olympiad of schoolchildren" (2020) Medalist of Olympiad of schoolchildren "Fiztech" in mathematics (2020) Medalist of regional stage in All-Russian Olympiad of schoolchildren of CS and ICT (2019)

## OTHER COURSES

Summer School of Russian Association of Artificial Intelligence (2021) Tinkoff Generation Algorithms school (2019) Samsung IT-school (2018) SIS (2016 — 2018)